A Finding Aid to the Lillian and Frederick Kiesler Papers, circa 1910s-2003, bulk 1958-2000, in the Archives of American Art AAA.kieslill
Archives of American Art
- Lillian Kiesler papers, circa 1910s-2003; Series 1; (Box 1-39, 47-52, OV 53-55; 41.1 linear feet)
  - Biographical Material, 1911-2002, undated; 1.1
    - Keys to Bank Studio, undated (Box 48, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 1, Folder 15.
  - Correspondence, 1911-2001, undated; 1.2
    Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler is extensive and includes letters from museums, galleries, collectors, artists, directors, writers, actors, musicians, family and friends. Business correspondence contains information about sales and gifts of artwork, Lillian Kiesler's support of performances and institutions, invitations, and character references. Among the correspondents are Harold Diamond, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, The Whitney Museum of American Art, The University of Iowa Museum of Art, and Erick Hawkins Dance Foundation.
    Among Lillian Kiesler's personal correspondence are letters and greeting cards from friends, family, artists, and researchers and scholars, including Etel Adnan, Alcopley, Fritz Bultman, Steve Buscemi, Mike Diamond, Burgoyne Diller, Lucia Dlugoszewski, Piero Dorazio, Jean Dubuffet, Jay Gottlieb, Erick Hawkins, Burgess Meredith, Henry Miller, James Purdy, and Herrel Thomas. Some correspondence contains original artwork, photographs, and audio cassettes created by the sender. Of interest is a letter from Harry Holtzman postmarked March 13, 1935 describing his initial meeting with Mondrian, and an undated letter from E.B. Gordon describing Henry Miller in Paris.
    Where there are envelopes, the letter is filed in front of the envelope. Business correspondence is arranged chronologically first, followed by personal correspondence arranged alphabetically by last name and miscellaneous correspondence filed chronologically by decade.
    - Business Correspondence, 1946-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Business Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Business Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Business Correspondence, 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Business Correspondence, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Abbott, Berenice, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Adnan, Etel, 1977-1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 14-15)
      Includes original artwork.
    - Andres, Jo, Steve and Lucien Buscemi, 1979-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - Avery, Sally (Michel), 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Barnet, Will, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Barnstone, Gertrude, 1972-2001, undated (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
    - Bartos, Martha, 1974-1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Baumgartner, Frances, 1976-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Beall, Paulette, 1975-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Berkman, Len, 1977-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Blaine, Nell, 1969-1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Bouchard, Diane, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Bultman, Fritz and Jeanne, 1965-1999, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Candido, Nancy Meehan and Anthony, 1974-2001, undated (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
    - Chao, S. Chen "Sunshine", 1946-1949 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1965-1969, undated (Box 3, Folder 10-12)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1970-1979, undated (Box 3, Folder 13-16)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1980-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1980-1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1990-1999, undated (Box 4, Folder 2-5)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 2000-2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Charlton, Maryette, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Charlton, Maryette, Correspondence to Maryette Charlton, 1965-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cohen, Elsa Kahl, 1979-1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Copley, Al, 1975-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Corman, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Court, Paula and Robert Fila, 1994-2001 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Cundiff, Selden, 1980-1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Deem, George, 1981, 1998-2000 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Delaney, Margaret, 1964-1966 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Dickey, Tina, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Diller, Burgoyne, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Dlugoszewski, Lucia, 1958-1999, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Dodi, 1988-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Donnelley, Helen, 1911, 1951-1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Dorazio, Piero, Virginia and Justin, 1974-2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Doty, Hazel, 1964-1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Douglas, Scott, 1983-1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Dubuffet, Jean, 1952-1959 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Evans, Degan, 1963-1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Fahlström, Yvonne (Najar), 1975-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Fahlström, Yvonne (Najar), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Fahlström, Yvonne (Najar), 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Fahlström, Yvonne (Najar), 1990-1998, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Fitch, Noel Riley, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Ford, Gordon Onslow, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Frankenberg, Lloyd and Loren, 1948, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Fujitomi, Yasuo, 1987-1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Gentilcore, Angela, Kevin and Ava Ryan, 1985-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
    - Giles, Mary, 1975-1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Goeritz, Mathias, 1969, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Goldberg, Pauline, 1996-2000, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Goldberg, RoseLee, 1977-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Gordon, E.B. "Betty", 1940, 1953-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Gottlieb, Jay, 1977-2001, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Greif, Martin, 1989-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Herrmann, Christopher, 1994-1999, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Hobbs, Robert, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Hodges, Alice, 1942, 1954-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 20-21)
    - Holland, Betty Lou, 1991-2001 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Holtzman, Harry, 1934-1935, 1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Iobst, Anne and Lucy Sexton, 1996-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Jesurun, John, 1987-2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Kamler, Richard, 1981-1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Katz, Edith, 1986-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 1969-1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Oversized material housed in OV 53.
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 1998-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, 2000-2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Kiang, Jacqueline, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, 1965-1999, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Kiesler, Steffi, 1948-1963, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Kleege, Laura, 1977-1981 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Kolb, Barbara, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Lesák, Barbara, 1987-2001 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Levy, Julien, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Lubar, Cindy Bishop, 1977-2001, undated; 1 cassette tapes (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - Luyken, Gunda, 1996-2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Manry, Lenita, 1940, 1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - McCoy, Jason, 1988-2001, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - McDowell, Carol, 1987-2000, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Meredith, Burgess, 1987-1996, undated; 1 Electronic discs (CD) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Miles, Jeanne, 1974-1984 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Miller, Bettie C., 1985-2000 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Miller, Henry, 1938, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Miller, Stephen, 1977-1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Miller, Tim, 1983-1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
    - Montgomery, Chandler, 1955-1983, undated (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
    - Moore, Rebecca, 1984-1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Newlin, Jeanne (Harvard Theatre Collection), 1973-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Stauffer, Marjorie, 1965-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - O'Brien, Patricia, 1978-1991, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Purdy, James, 1987-1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Roberts, Dan, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Rowley, Ellen, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Ryan, Virginia, 1984-2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 17-18)
    - Seitz, Irma, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Snyder, Scott, 1991-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Spender, Matthew, 1991-1997 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Tawney, Lenore, 1968-1982, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Temkin, Ann, 1991-1999 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - ten Haeff, Ingelborg, 1979-1998, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Terry, Megan and JoAnn Schmidman, 1972-1989, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Tetley, Glen, 1976-1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Thomas, Herrel George, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Thome, Diane, 1976-2000, undated; 2 cassette tapes (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Thome, Joel, 1975-1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Thompson, Alden, 1969-1981 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Varese, L., 1971-1981 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Véret, Jean-Louis and Helene, 1977-1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - von Brockdorff, Louise "Fifi" Medbury, 1970-1974, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Warren, Ron, 1995-1998 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Willard, Helen, 1974-1978, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Wilson, Bob, 1997-1999, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Winslow, Kirk, 1972-2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Wolf, Marion, 1975-1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Zaruba, Al (A. Scott Harmon), 1992-1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Zetina, Armando, 1990-1998 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1934-1939, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1940-1949, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1951-1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1961-1969, undated (Box 8, Folder 20-21)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1970-1979, undated (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1970-1979, undated; 1 cassette tapes (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1980-1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 3-10)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1990-1999, undated (Box 9, Folder 11-13)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 1990-1999, undated (Box 10, Folder 1-9)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, 2000-2001, undated (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - Chronological Correspondence to Lillian Kiesler, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Illustrated correspondence from Josephine Kiang, undated (Box OV 53)
      Oversized material from Box 6, Folder 7.
  - Legal and Financial Records, 1938-2001, undated; 1.3
    Legal and Financial Records contains files related to Lillian Kiesler's estate and finances such as burial plans and will. There is one folder containing Maryette Charlton's legal papers concerning her will. It is arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - 56 Seventh Avenue, 1979-1988, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Burial Plans, 1984, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Financial Papers, 1938, 1957-2001 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
    - Legal Papers, 1973-2001, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Legal Papers, Maryette Charlton, 1974-1999, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Teaching Files, 1938-1994, undated; 1.4
    Teaching files includes Lillian Kiesler's teaching plans and reference materials, essays, pamphlets, class lists, correspondence from schools, student artwork and essay assignments, notebooks, writings on teaching, and a book of weaving samples. Also included are writings about teaching art and lesson plans by Kiesler's mentor and friend, New York University professor Chandler Montgomery, including a 1994 printing of "The Making of an Art Teacher: An Unfinished Memoir." Additional related correspondence may be found in Correspondence, 1911-2001, undated (Subseries 1.2). Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Certificates and Reports, 1945, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Conferences and Conventions, 1946, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Embroidery and Weaving Samples with Clippings, 1952-1956, undated (Box 11, Folder 9-10)
    - Greenwich House, 1946-1950, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - New York University, Daily Plan Book and Class Cards, circa 1966 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - New York University, Early Childhood and Elementary Education, 1952-1994, undated (Box 11, Folder 13-14)
    - Notebooks, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Printed Material, Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Clippings, 1938-1958, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Queens College, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Student Work, 1963-1965, undated (Box 11, Folder 18-20)
    - Teaching and Diary Notes, circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Transparencies of Artwork, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Woodward School, 1945-1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Writings, 1947-1949, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Printed Material, Exhibition Catalogs, Announcements, and Clippings, 1938-1958, undated (Box OV 53)
      Oversized material from Box 11, Folder 16.
  - Exhibition and Performance Files, 1945-2002, undated; 1.5
    Exhibition and performance files contain correspondence, photographs, artwork, printed materials, scripts, rehearsal schedules, reviews, monographs and notes related to Kiesler's exhibitions and peformances dating from the 1970s-2001. Among the directors, artists and writers found in this subseries are Jo Andres, Steve Buscemi, Cindy Lugar, Tim Miller and James Purdy. This subseries is arranged first by exhibitions followed by performances. Folders are then arranged in chronological order.
    - Exhibitions, 1974-2002, undated; 1.5.1
      - "Flower Paintings and Members' Show,", 1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - The University of Iowa Museum of Art Permanent Collection, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - "An Artist's Christmas: Holiday Images by American Artists, 1880-1990", 1990-1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Various Exhibitions, 1945-2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
        Oversized materials housed in OV 53.
      - Proposed Exhibition, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - NYU Art Faculty Exhibit at James Gallery poster, undated (Box OV 53)
        Oversized material from Box 12, Folder 4.
    - Performances, 1961-2001, undated; 1.5.2
      - List of Performances, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "Everyday Business," Cindy Lubar, 1978-1980, undated (Box 12, Folder 7-10)
      - "Serves You Right," Steve Buscemi and Mark Boone Junior, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - "Before Your Eyes," Jo Andres, 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - "Total Rain," Richard Foreman, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - "Losing Sight, Not Vision," Jo Andres, 1989-1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - "Dreaming Out Loud," Jo Andres, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 15)
        Oversized material housed in Box 48, Folders 3 and 8; see also Box 37, Folder 21.
      - "Roy Cohn/Jack Smith," Ron Vawter, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - "The Hinger," Rebecca Moore, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 17)
        See also Box 37, Folder 21.
      - John Cage Readings, 1994-1999 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - "Martha's World," Agnes de Mille, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 19)
        See also Box 39, Folder 6.
      - Various Performances, 1977-2001, undated (Box 12, Folder 20-22)
      - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1985-1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
        Oversized material housed in Box 48, Folders 4-5.
      - Miscellaneous Papers and Letters, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - Monographs, Silence, John Cage, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Monographs, A Year From Monday, John Cage, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Monographs, "TDR: The Drama Review", Winter 1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Monographs, For the Working Artist: A survival guide for artists, Judith Luther, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
        Dedicated to Lillian Kiesler and Maryette Charlton.
      - Monographs, Shirts and Skin, Tim Miller, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 5)
        Inscribed.
      - "Dreaming Out Loud" Clippings, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 3)
        Oversized materials from Box 12, Folder 15.
      - Printed Material, Magazine (article about Steve Buscemi), 1997 (Box 48, Folder 4)
        Oversized materials from Box 12, Folder 23.
      - Printed Material, Posters, 1986-1990 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - "Dreaming Out Loud," Framed Poster, 1990 (Box 48, Folder 8)
      - "Emily Likes the TV" poster, undated (Box OV 53)
        Oversized materials from Box 12, Folders 20-23.
  - Artwork, 1958-2001, undated; 1.6
    Artwork includes original drawings, sketches, and notes by Lillian Kiesler, as well as photographs and drawings by her friends. Included are photographs by Bob Del Fredici, drawings by Piero Dorazio, and notes to Frederick Kiesler from Lillian Kiesler. The folders are arranged alphabetically by artist's last name.
    - By Lillian Kiesler, 1958-2001, undated (Box 13, Folder 6-8)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 48, Folder 6.
    - By Lillian Kiesler, Notes to Frederick Kiesler, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 48, Folder 7.
    - Others, Del Fredici, Bob, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Others, Dorazio, Piero, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Others, Dupin, Beatriz Luz, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Others, Unknown, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Others, Various, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - By Lillian Kiesler, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
      Oversized materials from Box 13, Folders 6-8.
    - By Lillian Kiesler, Notes to Frederick Kiesler, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
      Oversized materials from Box 13, Folder 9.
  - Subject Files, 1925, 1957-2000, undated; 1.7
    Subject files include collected materials about artists, friends, colleagues, performances, and organizations in which Lillian Kiesler supported. Materials include correspondence, playbills, reviews, resumes and biographies, and writings. This subseries is arranged alphabetically by the artist's or organization's name.
    - Andres, Jo, 1986-1996, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Anthology Film Archives, 1975-1995, undated (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
    - Barry, Judith, 1993-2000, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
      See also Box 20, Folder 6 and Box 39, Folder 3.
    - Bultman, Fritz, 1962-1973 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1981-1995, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Charlton, Maryette, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Dlugoszewski, Lucia and Erick Hawkins, 1957-1995, undated (Box 13, Folder 22-23)
    - Duchamp, Marcel, 1965-1998, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Goodman, Cynthia, Millennium Monument and World Peace Bell, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      See also Box 39, Folder 7.
    - Meredith, Burgess, undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - National Tribute to Alexander Calder; "Socrate," Eric Satie (1977), 1977-1979, undated (Box 14, Folder 4-5)
    - Varèse, Edgard, 1960, 1981, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - von Brockdorff, Louise (Fifi) Medbury, 1925-1977, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Watts, Chi, 1988, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Winslow, Kirk, 1972, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Printed Material, 1930-2002, undated; 1.8
    Printed material includes collected postcards, magazines and magazine articles about art and performance, newspaper clippings about fellow artists, invitations and announcements, and exhibition catalogs. Found are signed exhibition catalogs of Loren MacIver, Dina Ghen, Lenore Tawney, and Toshiko Takaezu, and a reprint article inscribed by Alcopley. Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1949-1995, undated (Box 14, Folder 10-12)
      Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folder 1.
    - Exhibition Catalogs, signed, 1970-1988 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Exhibition Posters, 1947 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folder 2.
    - Invitations and Announcements, 1944, 1950 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Invitations and Announcements, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Invitations and Announcements, 1980-1989 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Invitations and Announcements, 1990-1997 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Invitations and Announcements, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Invitations and Announcements, 2000-2001 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folder 3.
    - Invitations and Announcements, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Magazine Clippings and Articles, 1930-2000, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Magazine Clippings and Articles, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Magazines, Journals, and Bulletins, 1936-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folder 4.
    - Magazines, Journals, and Bulletins, 1990-2000, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Oversized material housed in Box 49, Folder 5.
    - Miscellaneous, 1948, 1990, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 49, Folder 6.
    - Musical Scores, 1960, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 49, Folders 7-8.
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1977-2001, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
      Oversized materials housed in Box 49, Folder 10.
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1983-2000, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Pamphlets, 1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Postcards, 1975, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Reprint Article, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      Inscribed by Al Copley.
    - Exhibition Catalog, undated (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folders 10-12.
    - Exhibition Posters, Jean Dubuffet "Portraits", 1947 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 14.
    - Invitations and Announcements, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 3)
      Oversized material from Box 14, Folder 20.
    - "The A.W.A. Bulletin", 1936 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 3.
    - Magazine, "Index", 1999 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 4.
    - Miscellaneous, Poster (rolled), undated (Box 49, Folder 6)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 6.
    - Musical Score, "Music for Left Ear in a Small Room, No.11" by Lucia Dlugoszewski, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 7.
    - Musical Score, "Sunflower Space" by Diane Thome (with artwork by Lillian Kiesler), undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Le Monde Newspaper, 1977 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Oversized material from Box 15, Folder 8.
    - Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 2001 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Lillian Kiesler Library, 1936-2000; 1.9
    Lillian Kiesler's library includes numerous monographs written by friends or about friends, most with inscriptions by authors. Included are books about and inscribed by Max Weiler and Piero Dorazio, as well as an inscribed first edition of Henry Miller's Black Spring (1936) and a 1937 monograph by Harry Holtzman, American Abstract Artists. Folders are arranged alphabetically by author's last name.
    - Adnan, Etel. Journey to Mount Tamalpais. Sausalito: The Post-Apollo Press, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      Inscribed by author.
    - Aldan, Daisy. A Golden Story. New York: Folder Editions, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Inscribed by Dina Ghen, 1991.
    - Aldan, Daisy. In Passage. New York: Folder Editions, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      Inscribed by author, 1989.
    - Alschuler, Rose and La Berta Weiss Hattwick. Painting and Personality: A Study of Young Children. Chicago: The University of Chicago Press, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      Inscribed by Fredrick Kiesler, 1952.
    - Carré, Louis. Entretien de Fernand Léger avec Blaise Cendrars et Louis Carré sur le Paysage dans l'oeuvre de Léger. Paris, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Cometti, Jean-Pierre, ed. Aspects de Wittgenstein, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      Inscribed by Antonia Soulez.
    - Cooper, Jackie, ed. Mackintosh Architecture: The Complete Buildings and Selected Projects. New York: Rizzoli, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 19)